<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ian Teda</title>
    <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ian Teda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ianteda.com/v2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 16 - The Professional Engineer</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-16-the-professional-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-16-the-professional-engineer/</guid>
      <description>With great power comes great responsibility.— Uncle Ben
 Collections of information get abstracted away into what we call professions. Doctors, lawyers, electricians, engineers, etc. It isn’t possible for each of us to know everything, so we rely on professions. And we rely on professionals to understand that information. Being a professional is about being a trustee of information.
We rely on professionals to grow and to peer review there field of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 15 - We Are All Paid To Think</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-15-paid-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-15-paid-to-think/</guid>
      <description>Thinking is the hardest work there is, which is probably the reason why so few engage in it.&amp;ndash; Henry Ford
 Back in the day, when I was going through University I worked as a labourer from time to time for a good friend of mine Cam. Cam ran his own building company and I did occasional work when business was busy or an extra pair of hands was needed to hold a nail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 14 - The KISS Principle</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-14-kiss-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-14-kiss-principle/</guid>
      <description>Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication.&amp;ndash; Leonardo da Vinci
 Keep It Simple Stupid (KISS).
It isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to make things difficult, anybody can do that. Even someone stupid. The skill and art, is in making it simple.
Simple is: the essence; the most important part; something that is repeatable; provides the same outcome; that if you remember anything, remember this;
The KISS principle was first adopted by the US Navy1, for the design of their naval ships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 13 - Learn to ask good questions.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-13-good-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-13-good-questions/</guid>
      <description>Successful people ask better questions, and as a result, they get better answers.&amp;ndash; Tony Robbins
 Questions are the cornerstone of communication &amp;ndash; aka leadership, problem solving and learning. So being able to ask good questions is the key to good communication, efficient problem solving and effective learning.
There is an art to asking a good questions, because after all if you put garbage in you get garbage out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 12 - When you have the choice, always start with the hardest part.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-12-hard-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-12-hard-things/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the hardest thing and the right thing are the same.The Fray - All at Once
 Anything worthwhile is hard. Because it is the difficulties that make it unique and it is the uniqueness that makes it valuable.
 Difficult roads often lead to beautiful destinations. - Unknown
 When you have the choice, always start with the hardest part first. By achieving the hardest part first you gain a strategic and physiological advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 11 - Finding Time</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-11-finding-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-11-finding-time/</guid>
      <description>Time is the measurer of all things, but is itself immeasurable, and the grand discloser of all things, but is itself undisclosed.  - Charles Caleb Colton
 It all boils down to time. After all, money is just the value we place on time. It makes sense then, that the most valuable gift you can give is your time. Because, we don&amp;rsquo;t know how much we have, we cannot make more of it and once it has turned into yesterday we cannot get it back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 10 - Pop quiz, what is the number?</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-10-pop-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-10-pop-quiz/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;rsquo;t know, what you don&amp;rsquo;t know.- Unknown
 Never have truer words been spoken. It is always the unknown unknowns that get you. Because they blind side you when you are looking the other way.
 What gets measured gets managed.- Peter Drucker
 If you want people to focus on something, ask them to measure it. And pop quiz them each day about what the number is. The pop quiz will help:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 9 - Always start with the end in mind.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-9-always-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-9-always-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t change the direction of the wind, but I can adjust my sails to always reach my destination. &amp;ndash; Jimmy Dean
 Always start with the end in mind. What is the ideal outcome? What is your destination? And then breakdown the journey into manageable pieces, reverse engineering the path to get there.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a destination, you don&amp;rsquo;t have direction. And if you don&amp;rsquo;t have direction you are lost, going around and around in circles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 8 - Keep one eye open and your ear to the ground.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/2017-05-03-rule-8-eye-and-ear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/2017-05-03-rule-8-eye-and-ear/</guid>
      <description>Blinding ignorance does mislead us. O! Wretched mortals, open your eyes! - Leonardo da Vinci
 It is easy to focus on your work and for your work to become your world. But it is equally important to keep the bigger picture in mind and maintain perspective. To learn the context of where your work fits into the bigger machine, what external forces could affect your work and how you might be able to help others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 7 - Do not walk past it.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-7-do-not-walk-past-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-7-do-not-walk-past-it/</guid>
      <description>The standard you walk past, is the standard you accept.  - David Morrison
 Be it a safety concern, poor workmanship or bad behaviour if you close your eyes and walk past it then you are accepting it. You are saying that you are not concerned and feel free to keep doing it without correction.
To live by this rule means difficult conversations, extra work and extra responsibility. Not everyone goes looking for or wants these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 6 - Respect the 6 Ps.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-6-the-6-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-6-the-6-ps/</guid>
      <description>The 6 Ps: Prior Planning Prevents Piss Poor Performance.  - U.S. Army
 Respect the 6 Ps:
 Prior Planning Prevents Piss Poor Performance  1 - Prior  Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe.  - Abraham Lincoln
 Don&amp;rsquo;t leave your planning to the last moment. Insteed, dive into the detail early to make sure a lack of planning doesn&amp;rsquo;t become somebody else&amp;rsquo;s priority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 5 - The early bird catches the worm, and enjoys the fruits of its labor.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-5-start-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-5-start-early/</guid>
      <description>The early bird catches the worm.  - William Camden
 Always try to start work early because it demonstrates that you want your job and you want to be there. Most things can be taught, enthusiasim and desire, for the most part, cannot be.
Getting to work early gives you the oppurtunity to set the destiny of construction for the day. Otherwise you will be chasing your tail all day, trying to get construction moving in the direction you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 4 - Relationships, say hello because success is largely a result of those around you.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-4-relationships-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-4-relationships-success/</guid>
      <description>You are the average of the five people you spend the most time with. Jim Rohn
 From construction of the project to your career, success — however you measure it — is largely a result of the people around you. So make an effort to build relationships with everyone, from the project director to the members of the workforce. And the best way to build relationships is to say hello and make an effort to learn peoples name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 3 - Give me good news, give bad news. Just don&#39;t give me surprises.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-3-dont-give-me-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-3-dont-give-me-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Be in control of your destiny, by getting out in front of issues and avoiding suprises.
 As a manager, I want to know about the good news and the bad news. But don’t bring me surprises. Surprises indicate a lack of understanding and ownership of what you are responsible for.
This rule is no better illustrated then in cost forecasting. If your quantities, rates and costs continually move around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 2 - When faced with opposing views, often the answer is both.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-2-opposing-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-2-opposing-views/</guid>
      <description>Much of life is a dichotomy, a contradiction and construction life is no different.
 When faced with what seem like mutually exclusive and opposing views, often the answer is both. Much of life is a dichotomy, a contradiction and construction life is no different. The skill comes in first realizing this, being comfortable with the contradictions and knowing how to find the balance.
Rule 2, is a little bit of an abstract concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 1 - Your job is to make money. By building it safely, building it once and leaving a positive legacy.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-1-what-is-your-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/rule-1-what-is-your-job/</guid>
      <description>Rule 1 - Your job is to make money. By building it safely, building it once and leaving a positive legacy.
 “What do think your job is?”. It is a question I like to ask graduate engineers as they are starting in construction, because it helps to orientate them as they start life in the workforce and start in construction.
What is your job? Your job as a construction engineer is to make money for your employer, XYZ Constructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Habit Loop</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-habit-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-habit-loop/</guid>
      <description>A habit is something you can do without thinking — which is why most of us have so many of them.  Frank A. Clark.
 We are, for the most part a collection of habits. A collection of emotional, physical and intellectual habits, systematically organised for our brains optimisation. Manifesting themselves in our character, businesses, social groups and cultures.
It might appear that the choices we make each day are the product of a well thought out conscious decision, but they are not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Habit Modification Framework</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-habit-modification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-habit-modification/</guid>
      <description>Your beliefs become your thoughts; Your thoughts become your words; Your words become your actions; Your actions become your habits; Your habits become your values; Your values become your destiny.  Mahatma Ghandi.
 It is our habits that influence our actions, and it is our actions that define our character. It is what we do, our habits, not what we say that people judge use on.
Good habits are hard to form, and take continuous effort to maintain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The API Design Guide</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/programming/the-api-design-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/programming/the-api-design-guide/</guid>
      <description>An API allows one piece of software talking to another piece of software
 Definitions Some terms used in this guide and there definitions:
 API - Application Programming Interface, an interface for one piece of software to talk to another; Collection - A collection of resources found at an endpoint; Consumer (Client) - A client computer application making requests of the API; cURL - A command line tool for getting and sending files using URL syntax; Endpoint - An API URL on a Server which represents either a Resource or a Collection; Granularity - The level of detailed returned in the request response; HTTP - A protocol for communicating over networks, aka the internet; Idempotent (Stateless) - Side-effect free, can happen multiple times without affecting the data state; Resource - A single instance of an object in an endpoint request response; REST (RESTful) - Representational State Transfer, an architectural style for the design of network-based software; SSL - Secure Socket Layer, the standard security technology for establishing an encrypted link between a web server and a browser URL - Uniform Resource Locator and is a reference (an address) to a resource on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turtle Mindset</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-turtle-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-turtle-mindset/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Turtles carry their homes on their backs.&amp;rdquo; Running her finger over the tattoo, she tells him what her dad told her: &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re exposed and hidden at the same time. They&amp;rsquo;re a symbol of strength and perseverance.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ndash; Christina Baker Kline
 In the Aesop&amp;rsquo;s Fables &amp;ldquo;The Tortoise and the Hare&amp;rdquo;, the turtle wins the race not by aiming for big (fast) wins, instead he stays on his path with a single minded focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Passion Falsity</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-passion-falsity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-passion-falsity/</guid>
      <description>Life isn’t about finding yourself. Life is about creating yourself.  &amp;ndash; GEORGE BERNHARD SHAW
 Life isn&amp;rsquo;t something you chip away at until you find your passion waiting inside. Life is something you build upon slowly over time, it is something you create1. So instead of discovering yourself, create yourself. Become a master craftsman of your life.
Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to find their passion. It&amp;rsquo;s a romantic notion afterall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Personal Branding Defence</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-personal-branding-defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-personal-branding-defence/</guid>
      <description>Start by knowing what you want and who you are, build credibility around it and deliver it online in a compelling way.  — Krista Neher
 You are a brand If you are not branding yourself, others are doing it for you. Going to a job interview, leasing a house or doing business then your name will be googled. Personal branding is about managing your name in a world of misinformation, disinformation, and semi-permanent Google records1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Model Definition</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-mental-model-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-mental-model-definition/</guid>
      <description>Man seeks for himself a simplified and lucid image of the world.  &amp;ndash; Albert Einstein
 Mental models simplify the world around us so we can make sense of our surroundings. They are an abstraction of reality, a simplification of an incomprehensibly world so our limited cognitive capabilities can process all our inputs without overload.
I wanted to explore and better understand mental models and what better way to understand a topic then to try to explain it to someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gulp Jekyll Workflow - Part 1 Design Pattern</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/programming/gulp-jekyll-workflow-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/programming/gulp-jekyll-workflow-1/</guid>
      <description>Always start with the end in mind. So you know what direction to travel  — Ian Teda 
 Keeping the end in mind, I listed four design criteria (patterns) to target when writting Gulp tasks. I wanted my workflow to be modern, simple, configurable and modulised.
Design Criteria/Patterns
 Use ES2015, ECMAScript 2015 (modern): Why? Get accustom to new JavaScript features before they become mainstream. Command Line Interface (simple): Why?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gulp, Jekyll, Github Pages &amp; Cloudflare Mixture</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/programming/the-gulp-jekyll-github-pages-cloudflare-mixture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/programming/the-gulp-jekyll-github-pages-cloudflare-mixture/</guid>
      <description>Flexible, simple, fast, secure &amp;amp; https. Total cost, $15AUD for domain registration.  — Ian Teda 
 Web technologies for development hosting and security are vast. With proponents singing their own praises. At the start of my ianteda.com project 1 I looked around at the options.
Wordpress{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;} serves up over 26%2 of the internet. Been there done that, so I crossed it off the list .
I almost settled on Ghost{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video - The Cotter Dam Intake Tower Explanation</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/2016-03-02-the-cotter-dam-intake-tower-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering/2016-03-02-the-cotter-dam-intake-tower-explanation/</guid>
      <description>A short video featuring yours truly, and the construction of the intake tower on the Cotter Dam project.
  Video &amp;amp; Cover Image Credit: Icon Water{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;} &amp;amp; Richard Snashall{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idea Value Proposition</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-idea-value-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-idea-value-proposition/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Daring ideas are like chessmen moved forward. They may be beaten, but they may start a winning game.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ndash; Johann Wolfgang von Goethe
 Ideas are easy, cheap even. It is the execution that is hard and because it is hard it is worth millions. If the execution wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard everyone would be doing it. And if everyone was doing it, then it would be worthless and quickly become a race to the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bold Mistake Instruction</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-bold-mistake-instruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/the-bold-mistake-instruction/</guid>
      <description>All courses of action are risky, so prudence is not in avoiding danger (it&amp;rsquo;s impossible), but calculating risk and acting decisively. Make mistakes of ambition and not mistakes of sloth. Develop the strength to do bold things, not the strength to suffer. &amp;ndash; Chapter III: Of Mixed Princedoms1
 {: .book-cover}{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;}
Life is risk, it cannot be avoided so do not let the possibility of being wrong prevent action. An indecision is still a decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mastermind Brief</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-mastermind-brief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-mastermind-brief/</guid>
      <description>No two minds ever come together without thereby creating a third, invisible intangible force, which may be likened to a third mind [the master mind].  &amp;ndash; Napoleon Hill
 {: .book-cover}
The phrase Mastermind Group (MMG) was first coined by Napoleon Hill in his 1937 book &amp;ldquo;Think and Grow Rich&amp;rdquo;. A MMG can be thought of as a peer advisory board that meets with the aim of sharpening the groups personal and business skills so they can achieve optimum outcomes1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Leadership Style Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-leadership-style-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-leadership-style-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Styles are tailor made to different situations. Different leaders must have their own styles and these styles must be able to adapt to different people and situations.&amp;rdquo;  &amp;ndash; John Ng
 You need to find your own style of leadership, one that complements your character. However, good leaders use all three styles depending on the dynamics.
Leadership Styles The father of leadership is arguably the psychologist Kurt Lewin{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ianteda.com Directive</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-ianteda-com-directive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/leadership/the-ianteda-com-directive/</guid>
      <description>{: .img-circle }
Hello and thank you for visiting ianteda.com, my little corner of the Internet.
I created ianteda.com to be useful. By sharing content around ideas, thoughts and projects I am working on. Second to being useful, I wanted to build and manage my - Ian Teda - professional image, brand and authority.
The concept of being useful came from Scott Adams{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;} the creator of the Dilbert Cartoons. The answer to the ultimate question of Life, the Universe, and Everything is not 42{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;} but &amp;ldquo;be useful&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to my Sons</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/a-letter-to-sons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/a-letter-to-sons/</guid>
      <description>Live, love, be generous, show respect and give thanks.
Know who you are and remember were you came from, but always look forward to were you are going.
Time is the most valuable thing you have, as death comes to us all. So spend it wisely and without regrets. Make peace with God, yourself, your family and your friends so that when the day comes for you to face the great divide, you face it without the fear (regret) of death in your heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey With Cancer</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/a-journey-with-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/creativity/a-journey-with-cancer/</guid>
      <description>I would like to acknowledge and thank all those that helped and supported my father on his final journey, and the Teda family after his passing. Your love is very much appreciated and heartfelt. Thank You.
His journey with cancer illustrates well his character, the person that he was and the life that he lived. He was:
 A husband A father A family man A lover A wise man A man with integrity Shined the light of life Had a spirit of adventure The desire to explore A determination A film maker A hard worker Enjoyment Holidays Courage Dignity Acceptance Skilled hands Finished the race  His journey with cancer, can best be described as a mysterious journey of unknown certainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Rule Book</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering-rule-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/engineering-rule-book/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Rule Book A list of rules for construction engineers:
 Rule 1 - Your job is to make money. By building it safely, building it once and leaving a positive legacy. Rule 2 - When faced with opposing views, often the answer is both. Rule 3 - Give me good news, give bad news. Just don&amp;rsquo;t give me surprises. Rule 4 - Relationships, say hello because success is largely a result of those around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What am I doing right now (January 2017)!</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/v2/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/v2/now/</guid>
      <description>Now Last updated 6th January 2017
Hanging out with the Wife and Boys in Sydney, while working on the Sydney Light Rail Design with GHD{:target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo;}.
Books Books I&amp;rsquo;m reading and why:
 Sh*t My Dad Sayss &amp;ndash; Laughing my arse of on the train, coming home from work. The Personal MBA: Master the Art of Business &amp;ndash; Learning about business. Nugget, after nugget of gold in this one. Had to press pause to take it all in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>