<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts on Ian Teda</title>
    <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Ian Teda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ianteda.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Is Hard, And That Is Good!</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/life-is-hard-and-that-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/life-is-hard-and-that-is-good/</guid>
      <description>A letter to my kids,
Real difficulties can be overcome; it is only the imaginary ones that are unconquerable.
Theodore N. Vail  Life is not all sun shine, unicorns and rainbows. Life is hard, it is meant to be hard and that is good!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Yourself, Be Yourself, Love Yourself</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/know-be-love-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/know-be-love-yourself/</guid>
      <description>A letter to my kids,
Nosce te ipsum, tu ipse esto, ama te ipsum. &amp;#39;know yourself, be yourself, love Yourself&amp;#39;
Quora  Know Yourself: Step back from the movie being played in your head and examine your habits, your motives and your desires from the outside in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hugo Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-hugo-acceleration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-hugo-acceleration/</guid>
      <description>Simply put, Hugo is way faster than Jekyll at building your site after pushing edits &amp;amp; commits.
Quora  My Jekyll build time was quickly growing and I was finding myself having to fix dependencies every time I felt the need to update Jekyll. I was getting frustrated, having to fight Jekyll when I wanted to be creating content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 16 - The Professional Engineer</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-16-the-professional-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-16-the-professional-engineer/</guid>
      <description>With great power comes great responsibility.
Uncle Ben  Collections of information get abstracted away into what we call professions. Doctors, lawyers, electricians, engineers, etc. It isn’t possible for each of us to know everything, so we rely on professions. And we rely on professionals to understand that information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 15 - We Are All Paid To Think</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-15-paid-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-15-paid-to-think/</guid>
      <description>Thinking is the hardest work there is, which is probably the reason why so few engage in it.
Henry Ford  Back in the day, when I was going through University I worked as a labourer from time to time for a good friend of mine Cam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 14 - The KISS Principle</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-14-the-kiss-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-14-the-kiss-principle/</guid>
      <description>Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication.
Leonardo da Vinci  Keep It Simple Stupid (KISS).
It isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to make things difficult, anybody can do that. Even someone stupid. The skill and art, is in making it simple.
Simple is: the essence; the most important part; something that is repeatable; provides the same outcome; that if you remember anything, remember this;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 13 - Learn To Ask Good Questions</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-13-good-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-13-good-questions/</guid>
      <description>Successful people ask better questions, and as a result, they get better answers.
Tony Robbins  Questions are the cornerstone of communication, leadership, problem solving and learning. So being able to ask good questions is the key to good communication, efficient problem solving and effective learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 12 - Start With The Hardest Part</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-12-hard-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-12-hard-things/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the hardest thing and the right thing are the same.
The Fray - All at Once  Anything worthwhile is hard. Because it is the difficulties that make it unique and it is the uniqueness that makes it valuable.
Difficult roads often lead to beautiful destinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 11 - Finding Time</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-11-finding-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-11-finding-time/</guid>
      <description>Time is the measurer of all things, but is itself immeasurable, and the grand discloser of all things, but is itself undisclosed.
Charles Caleb Colton  It all boils down to time. After all, money is just the value we place on time. It makes sense then, that the most valuable gift you can give is your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 10 - Measure It</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-10-measure-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-10-measure-it/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;#39;t know, what you don&amp;#39;t know.
Unknown  Never have truer words been spoken. It is always the unknown unknowns that get you. Because they blind side you when you are looking the other way.
What gets measured gets managed.
Peter Drucker  If you want people to focus on something, ask them to measure it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 9 - Start With The End In Mind</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-9-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-9-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;#39;t change the direction of the wind, but I can adjust my sails to always reach my destination.
Jimmy Dean  Always start with the end in mind. What is the ideal outcome? What is your destination? And then breakdown the journey into manageable pieces, reverse engineering the path to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 8 - Keep One Eye Open And An Ear To The Ground</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-8-keep-one-eye-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-8-keep-one-eye-open/</guid>
      <description>Blinding ignorance does mislead us. O! Wretched mortals, open your eyes!
Leonardo da Vinci  It is easy to focus on your work and for your work to become your world. But it is equally important to keep the bigger picture in mind and maintain perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 7 - Do Not Walk Past It</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-7-do-not-walk-past-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-7-do-not-walk-past-it/</guid>
      <description>The standard you walk past, is the standard you accept.
David Morrison  Be it a safety concern, poor workmanship or bad behaviour if you close your eyes and walk past it then you are accepting it. You are saying that you are not concerned and feel free to keep doing it without correction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 6 - Respect The 6 Ps</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-6-respect-the-6-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-6-respect-the-6-ps/</guid>
      <description>The 6 Ps: Prior Planning Prevents Piss Poor Performance.
U.S. Army  Respect the 6 Ps:
 Prior Planning Prevents Piss Poor Performance  1 - Prior Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 5 - Start Early</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-5-start-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-5-start-early/</guid>
      <description>The early bird catches the worm.
William Camden  Always try to start work early because it demonstrates that you want your job and you want to be there. Most things can be taught, enthusiasm and desire, for the most part, cannot be.
Getting to work early gives you the opportunity to set the destiny of construction for the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 4 - Relationships Are Success</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-4-relationships-are-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-4-relationships-are-success/</guid>
      <description>You are the average of the five people you spend the most time with.
Jim Rohn  From construction of the project to your career, success — however you measure it — is largely a result of the people around you. So make an effort to build relationships with everyone, from the project director to the members of the workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 3 - Good News, Bad News And Surprises</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-3-dont-give-me-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-3-dont-give-me-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Be in control of your destiny, by getting out in front of issues and avoiding surprises.
 As a manager, I want to know about the good news and the bad news. But don’t bring me surprises. Surprises indicate a lack of understanding and ownership of what you are responsible for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 2 - Often The Answer Is Both</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-2-the-answer-is-both/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-2-the-answer-is-both/</guid>
      <description>Much of life is a dichotomy, a contradiction and construction life is no different.
 When faced with what seem like mutually exclusive and opposing views, often the answer is both. Much of life is a dichotomy, a contradiction and construction life is no different. The skill comes in first realizing this, being comfortable with the contradictions and knowing how to find the balance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 1 - Your Job Is To Make Money</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-1-make-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/rule-1-make-money/</guid>
      <description>Rule 1 - Your job is to make money. By building it safely, building it once and leaving a positive legacy.
 “What do think your job is?”. It is a question I like to ask graduate engineers as they are starting in construction, because it helps to orientate them as they start life in the workforce and start in construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Habit Modification</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-modification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-modification/</guid>
      <description>Your beliefs become your thoughts; Your thoughts become your words; Your words become your actions; Your actions become your habits; Your habits become your values; Your values become your destiny.
Mahatma Ghandi.  It is our habits that control our actions, and it is our actions that define our character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Habit Loop</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-loop/</guid>
      <description>A habit is something you can do without thinking — which is why most of us have so many of them.
Frank A. Clark.  We are, for the most part a collection of habits. A collection of emotional, physical and intellectual habits, systematically organised for our brains optimisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The API Design Guide</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-api-design-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-api-design-guide/</guid>
      <description>An API allows one piece of software talking to another piece of software
 Definitions Some terms used in this guide and there definitions:
 API - Application Programming Interface, an interface for one piece of software to talk to another; Collection - A collection of resources found at an endpoint; Consumer (Client) - A client computer application making requests of the API; cURL - A command line tool for getting and sending files using URL syntax; Endpoint - An API URL on a Server which represents either a Resource or a Collection; Granularity - The level of detailed returned in the request response; HTTP - A protocol for communicating over networks, aka the internet; Idempotent (Stateless) - Side-effect free, can happen multiple times without affecting the data state; Resource - A single instance of an object in an endpoint request response; REST (RESTful) - Representational State Transfer, an architectural style for the design of network-based software; SSL - Secure Socket Layer, the standard security technology for establishing an encrypted link between a web server and a browser URL - Uniform Resource Locator and is a reference (an address) to a resource on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turtle Mindset</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-turtle-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-turtle-mindset/</guid>
      <description>Turtles carry their homes on their backs. Running her finger over the tattoo, she tells him what her dad told her: They&amp;#39;re exposed and hidden at the same time. They&amp;#39;re a symbol of strength and perseverance.
Christina Baker Kline  In the Aesop&amp;rsquo;s Fables &amp;ldquo;The Tortoise and the Hare&amp;rdquo;, the turtle wins the race not by aiming for big (fast) wins, instead he stays on his path with a single minded focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Passion Falsity</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-passion-falsity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-passion-falsity/</guid>
      <description>Life isn’t about finding yourself. Life is about creating yourself.
George Bernhard Shaw  Life isn&amp;rsquo;t something you chip away at until you find your passion waiting inside. Life is something you build upon slowly over time, it is something you create1. So instead of discovering yourself, create yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Personal Branding Defence</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-personal-branding-defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-personal-branding-defence/</guid>
      <description>Start by knowing what you want and who you are, build credibility around it and deliver it online in a compelling way.
Krista Neher  You are a brand If you are not branding yourself, others are doing it for you. Going to a job interview, leasing a house or doing business then your name will be googled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Model Definition</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-mental-model-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-mental-model-definition/</guid>
      <description>Man seeks for himself a simplified and lucid image of the world.
Albert Einstein  Mental models simplify the world around us so we can make sense of our surroundings. They are an abstraction of reality, a simplification of an incomprehensibly world so our limited cognitive capabilities can process all our inputs without overload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gulp, Jekyll, Github Pages &amp; Cloudflare Mixture</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-gulp-jekyll-github-cloudflare-mixture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-gulp-jekyll-github-cloudflare-mixture/</guid>
      <description>Flexible, simple, fast, secure &amp;amp; https. Total cost, $15AUD for domain registration.
Ian Teda  Web technologies for development hosting and security are vast. With proponents singing their own praises. At the start of my ianteda.com project 1 I looked around at the options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intake Tower Explanation</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-intake-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-intake-explanation/</guid>
      <description>A short video featuring yours truly, and the construction of the intake tower on the Cotter Dam project.
  Video &amp;amp; Cover Image Credit: Icon Water &amp;amp; Richard Snashall</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idea Value Proposition</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-idea-value-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-idea-value-proposition/</guid>
      <description>Daring ideas are like chessmen moved forward. They may be beaten, but they may start a winning game.
Johann Wolfgang von Goethe  Ideas are easy, cheap even. It is the execution that is hard and because it is hard it is worth millions. If the execution wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard everyone would be doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bold Mistake Instruction</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-bold-mistake-instruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-bold-mistake-instruction/</guid>
      <description>All courses of action are risky, so prudence is not in avoiding danger (it&amp;#39;s impossible), but calculating risk and acting decisively. Make mistakes of ambition and not mistakes of sloth. Develop the strength to do bold things, not the strength to suffer.
Chapter III: Of Mixed Princedoms   Life is risk, it cannot be avoided so do not let the possibility of being wrong prevent action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mastermind Brief</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-mastermind-brief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-mastermind-brief/</guid>
      <description>No two minds ever come together without thereby creating a third, invisible intangible force, which may be likened to a third mind [the master mind]
Napoleon Hill   The phrase Mastermind Group (MMG) was first coined by Napoleon Hill in his 1937 book &amp;ldquo;Think and Grow Rich&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Leadership Style Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-leadership-style-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-leadership-style-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Styles are tailor made to different situations. Different leaders must have their own styles and these styles must be able to adapt to different people and situations.
John Ng  You need to find your own style of leadership, one that complements your character. That being said, a good leader use all three styles depending on the dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ianteda.com Directive</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-ianteda-com-directive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-ianteda-com-directive/</guid>
      <description>Hello and thank you for visiting ianteda.com, my little corner of the Internet.
I created ianteda.com to be useful. By sharing content around ideas, thoughts and projects I am working on. Second to being useful, I wanted to build and manage my - Ian Teda - professional image, brand and authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to my Sons</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-letter-to-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-letter-to-son/</guid>
      <description>Live, love, be generous, show respect and give thanks.
Know who you are and remember were you came from, but always look forward to were you are going.
Time is the most valuable thing you have, as death comes to us all. So spend it wisely and without regrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey With Cancer</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-journey-with-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-journey-with-cancer/</guid>
      <description>I would like to acknowledge and thank all those that helped and supported my father on end of his journey, and the Teda family after his passing. Your love is very much appreciated and heartfelt. Thank You.
His journey with cancer illustrates well his character, the person that he was and the life that he lived.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>