<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creativity Posts on Ian Teda</title>
    <link>https://ianteda.com/categories/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creativity Posts on Ian Teda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ianteda.com/categories/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Yourself, Be Yourself, Love Yourself.</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/know-yourself-be-yourself-love-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/know-yourself-be-yourself-love-yourself/</guid>
      <description>A letter to my kids,
 Nosce te ipsum, tu ipse esto, ama te ipsum. &amp;ldquo;know yourself, be yourself, love Yourself&amp;rdquo;
 Know Yourself: Step back from the movie being played in your head and examine your habits, your motives and your desires from the outside in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Habit Modification</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-modification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-modification/</guid>
      <description>Your beliefs become your thoughts; Your thoughts become your words; Your words become your actions; Your actions become your habits; Your habits become your values; Your values become your destiny.
Mahatma Ghandi.  It is our habits that influence our actions, and it is our actions that define our character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Habit Loop</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-habit-loop/</guid>
      <description>A habit is something you can do without thinking — which is why most of us have so many of them.
Frank A. Clark.  We are, for the most part a collection of habits. A collection of emotional, physical and intellectual habits, systematically organised for our brains optimisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Passion Falsity</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-passion-falsity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-passion-falsity/</guid>
      <description>Life isn’t about finding yourself. Life is about creating yourself.
George Bernhard Shaw  Life isn&amp;rsquo;t something you chip away at until you find your passion waiting inside. Life is something you build upon slowly over time, it is something you create1. So instead of discovering yourself, create yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Model Definition</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-mental-model-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-mental-model-definition/</guid>
      <description>Man seeks for himself a simplified and lucid image of the world.
Albert Einstein  Mental models simplify the world around us so we can make sense of our surroundings. They are an abstraction of reality, a simplification of an incomprehensibly world so our limited cognitive capabilities can process all our inputs without overload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bold Mistake Instruction</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-bold-mistake-instruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/the-bold-mistake-instruction/</guid>
      <description>All courses of action are risky, so prudence is not in avoiding danger (it&amp;#39;s impossible), but calculating risk and acting decisively. Make mistakes of ambition and not mistakes of sloth. Develop the strength to do bold things, not the strength to suffer.
Chapter III: Of Mixed Princedoms   Life is risk, it cannot be avoided so do not let the possibility of being wrong prevent action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to my Sons</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-letter-to-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-letter-to-son/</guid>
      <description>Live, love, be generous, show respect and give thanks.
Know who you are and remember were you came from, but always look forward to were you are going.
Time is the most valuable thing you have, as death comes to us all. So spend it wisely and without regrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey With Cancer</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-journey-with-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blog/a-journey-with-cancer/</guid>
      <description>I would like to acknowledge and thank all those that helped and supported my father on end of his journey, and the Teda family after his passing. Your love is very much appreciated and heartfelt. Thank You.
His journey with cancer illustrates well his character, the person that he was and the life that he lived.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>