<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Engineering Rule Book on Ian Teda</title>
    <link>https://ianteda.com/series/the-engineering-rule-book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Engineering Rule Book on Ian Teda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ianteda.com/series/the-engineering-rule-book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 16 - The Professional Engineer</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-16-the-professional-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-16-the-professional-engineer/</guid>
      <description>With great power comes great responsibility.
Uncle Ben  Collections of information get abstracted away into what we call professions. Doctors, lawyers, electricians, engineers, etc. It isn’t possible for each of us to know everything, so we rely on professions. And we rely on professionals to understand that information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 15 - We Are All Paid To Think</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-15-paid-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-15-paid-to-think/</guid>
      <description>Thinking is the hardest work there is, which is probably the reason why so few engage in it.
Henry Ford  Back in the day, when I was going through University I worked as a labourer from time to time for a good friend of mine Cam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 14 - The KISS Principle</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-14-the-kiss-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-14-the-kiss-principle/</guid>
      <description>Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication.
Leonardo da Vinci  Keep It Simple Stupid (KISS).
It isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to make things difficult, anybody can do that. Even someone stupid. The skill and art, is in making it simple.
Simple is: the essence; the most important part; something that is repeatable; provides the same outcome; that if you remember anything, remember this;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 13 - Learn To Ask Good Questions</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-13-good-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-13-good-questions/</guid>
      <description>Successful people ask better questions, and as a result, they get better answers.
Tony Robbins  Questions are the cornerstone of communication, leadership, problem solving and learning. So being able to ask good questions is the key to good communication, efficient problem solving and effective learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 12 - Start With The Hardest Part</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-12-hard-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-12-hard-things/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the hardest thing and the right thing are the same.
The Fray - All at Once  Anything worthwhile is hard. Because it is the difficulties that make it unique and it is the uniqueness that makes it valuable.
Difficult roads often lead to beautiful destinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 11 - Finding Time</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-11-finding-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-11-finding-time/</guid>
      <description>Time is the measurer of all things, but is itself immeasurable, and the grand discloser of all things, but is itself undisclosed.
Charles Caleb Colton  It all boils down to time. After all, money is just the value we place on time. It makes sense then, that the most valuable gift you can give is your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 10 - Measure It</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-10-measure-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-10-measure-it/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;#39;t know, what you don&amp;#39;t know.
Unknown  Never have truer words been spoken. It is always the unknown unknowns that get you. Because they blind side you when you are looking the other way.
What gets measured gets managed.
Peter Drucker  If you want people to focus on something, ask them to measure it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 9 - Start With The End In Mind</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-9-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-9-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;#39;t change the direction of the wind, but I can adjust my sails to always reach my destination.
Jimmy Dean  Always start with the end in mind. What is the ideal outcome? What is your destination? And then breakdown the journey into manageable pieces, reverse engineering the path to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 8 - Keep One Eye Open And An Ear To The Ground</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-8-keep-one-eye-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-8-keep-one-eye-open/</guid>
      <description>Blinding ignorance does mislead us. O! Wretched mortals, open your eyes!
Leonardo da Vinci  It is easy to focus on your work and for your work to become your world. But it is equally important to keep the bigger picture in mind and maintain perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 7 - Do Not Walk Past It</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-7-do-not-walk-past-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-7-do-not-walk-past-it/</guid>
      <description>The standard you walk past, is the standard you accept.
David Morrison  Be it a safety concern, poor workmanship or bad behaviour if you close your eyes and walk past it then you are accepting it. You are saying that you are not concerned and feel free to keep doing it without correction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 6 - Respect The 6 Ps</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-6-respect-the-6-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-6-respect-the-6-ps/</guid>
      <description>The 6 Ps: Prior Planning Prevents Piss Poor Performance.
U.S. Army  Respect the 6 Ps:
 Prior Planning Prevents Piss Poor Performance  1 - Prior Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 5 - Start Early</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-5-start-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-5-start-early/</guid>
      <description>The early bird catches the worm.
William Camden  Always try to start work early because it demonstrates that you want your job and you want to be there. Most things can be taught, enthusiasm and desire, for the most part, cannot be.
Getting to work early gives you the opportunity to set the destiny of construction for the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 4 - Relationships Are Success</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-4-relationships-are-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-4-relationships-are-success/</guid>
      <description>You are the average of the five people you spend the most time with.
Jim Rohn  From construction of the project to your career, success — however you measure it — is largely a result of the people around you. So make an effort to build relationships with everyone, from the project director to the members of the workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 3 - Good News, Bad News And Surprises</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-3-dont-give-me-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-3-dont-give-me-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Be in control of your destiny, by getting out in front of issues and avoiding surprises.
 As a manager, I want to know about the good news and the bad news. But don’t bring me surprises. Surprises indicate a lack of understanding and ownership of what you are responsible for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 2 - Often The Answer Is Both</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-2-the-answer-is-both/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-2-the-answer-is-both/</guid>
      <description>Much of life is a dichotomy, a contradiction and construction life is no different.
 When faced with what seem like mutually exclusive and opposing views, often the answer is both. Much of life is a dichotomy, a contradiction and construction life is no different. The skill comes in first realizing this, being comfortable with the contradictions and knowing how to find the balance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule 1 - Your Job Is To Make Money</title>
      <link>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-1-make-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ianteda.com/blogs/rule-1-make-money/</guid>
      <description>Rule 1 - Your job is to make money. By building it safely, building it once and leaving a positive legacy.
 “What do think your job is?”. It is a question I like to ask graduate engineers as they are starting in construction, because it helps to orientate them as they start life in the workforce and start in construction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>